moveforwardpt.com 2010-11-18

# Privacy Policy « moveforwardpt

## APTA – Privacy Policy for Our Web Site

We care about your privacy and have created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy and to assist you in using [www.apta.org](http://www.apta.org/), [www.moveforwardpt.com](http://www.moveforwardpt.com/) and any other Web sites we may launch in the future (collectively the “Web Site”).

This Privacy Policy is subject to change and applies only to information on the Web Site, and not to outside sites linked to by the Web Site. You may contact us at the following address with any questions, concerns or comments you may have:

American Physical Therapy Association  
Attention: Webmaster  
1111 North Fairfax Street  
Alexandria, VA 22314  
Phone: 703/684-2782 or 800/999-APTA (2782)  
Fax: 703/684-7343  
Email: [webmaster@apta.org](mailto:webmaster@apta.org)

## Data Collection

APTA does not collect via the Web Site names, e-mail addresses, or any other personal information unless it is voluntarily provided by site visitors. Visitors will be informed when the Web Site requires personal information (name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card number and/or other identifying information). APTA will not distribute this information to third-parties without your prior consent.

Data submitted by a user will be used for the express purpose described at the point of collection in APTA’s database and for statistical purposes to analyze user behavior. APTA will protect the information provided. APTA does not disclose, give, sell, or transfer personal information with third parties without the site visitor’s express permission. If demographic information is given to third parties, only aggregate information will be provided.

APTA may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with any legal requirements or with a legal process, or to protect and defend the rights or property of APTA or the personal safety of APTA employees or members of the public.

## E-Mail

APTA will make every attempt to protect any personal information submitted to us electronically. However, electronic email is not secure against interception. Any sensitive information submitted to the Web Site is provided at the risk of the sender. If you are concerned that the content of your communication is especially sensitive, you may consider sending it by postal mail instead.

## Cookies

Cookies are small files that allow us to track our users’ interaction with the Web Site. Cookies do not identify the user personally, just the computer used to access the Web Site. The Web Site uses session cookies. These files are generated whenever a user accesses the Web Site and they are terminated once the user leaves the Web Site. The Web Site does not use persistent cookies, which have to be deleted manually. If for some reason you don’t want your information collected via cookies, you should have the option to disable the cookie function through your Internet browser. However, some areas of the Web Site may require cookies to be enabled.

## External Links

The Web Site contains links to other external web sites. APTA is not responsible for the privacy policies, sites that may contain cookies, or the content of these external links. Please direct any questions or comments that you have to these external Web sites.

## Public Access

Please note that the Web Site contains discussion forums, message boards and other public or member based forums. Please note that any information that you provide in these forums may become public and/or available to all members and you must exercise caution when deciding to provide any information, including personal information. Although we try to protect personally identifiable information, APTA cannot guarantee the privacy of any information that you provide on these forums; accordingly, any information you provide is at your own risk. APTA is not responsible for maintaining the privacy or secrecy of any passwords or account information that you may have disclosed.

## Security

Your privacy is of the utmost importance to us, but due to legal and security matters that are beyond our control, we cannot guarantee that the information that you may provide to us, including personally identifiable information, is not disclosed to a third party. APTA incorporates reasonable safeguards to protect the security, integrity, completeness, accuracy, and privacy of the personal information that we collect. To assist in making the Web Site secure, we use the latest industry standards to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information, such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers (SSL), where appropriate. APTA has also put in place precautions to protect information from loss, misuse, and alteration. Only those APTA employees who need access to your information in order to do their job are allowed access. Our intent is to honor or exceed any U.S. legal requirements for health information privacy.

Thank you.
